(914) 967-0000 [care@ryekids.com](mailto:care@ryekids.com)

Select Page

[HOME](https://ryekids.com/) > [ABOUT](https://ryekids.com/about/) > [**OFFICE POLICIES**](https://ryekids.com/about/office-policies/)

Appointment Policy
------------------

Your appointment is reserved specifically for your child. Changes may affect many other patients. If a change or cancellation is unavoidable and conflicts arise, please call us at the office at least 48 business hours (2 days) in advance so that we may offer that time to another patient who is in need of care.

As a courtesy to you and your child, we contact you via phone, email, and/or text to confirm your child’s appointment. Please let the front staff know your preference, and we will make the appropriate arrangements. We usually email one week before appointments, and call the day before to confirm your scheduled appointment.

We make every possible attempt to see all patients at their scheduled appointment time. In rare instances, our schedule may be adjusted in order to accommodate an injured child or an emergency situation. Please accept our deepest apology in advance should this occur during your appointment.

We will provide your child with the same courtesy should the unfortunate need for emergency treatment arise.

Please plan to arrive 5 minutes or more before your scheduled appointment. This will allow time for the completion of any additional paperwork so that your child’s visit remains on time.

A parent or legal guardian should be present during the first visit in order to sign all legal documents and consent to treatment. With these appropriate forms, grandparents, au pairs, and caretakers are permitted to accompany children for subsequent appointments. It would be our pleasure to meet your extended family so that we may provide home care instructions to all of your child’s caretakers.

Privacy Policy
--------------

Our office understands the importance of protecting your personal information. Please be assured that the collection, use, and disclosure of your personal information will be done in accordance with the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act (HIPAA). We appreciate your understanding in helping Rye Pediatric Dentistry remain in compliance with this law.

_Disclaimer:_  
Our website is meant to provide general information to you and your family about pediatric dentistry. Since each child’s oral health needs are unique, the content of this website does not provide specific professional advice. It should not be used as a substitute for consulting with a pediatric dentist.

To obtain recommendations appropriate for your child, please contact us for an appointment or consult any pediatric dentist of your choice. We shall not be liable for any dental and oral health related problems allegedly arising from the information disclosed in our website.

Financial Policy
----------------

Arrangment of payment for professional services is due at the time dental treatment is provided. Every effort will be made to provide a treatment plan which fits your timetable and budget, and gives your child the best possible care.

The office accepts Visa, MasterCard, Discover, and American Express. In addition, we offer several financing options, including Care Credit and in house financial payment arrangements. We are a preferred provider with several insurance companies and will happily file insurance claims. Please contact the office by email or call us: (914) 967-0000 for more information.

Voted Best Dentist by  
Westchester Magazine

[HOME](https://ryekids.com/) > [ABOUT](https://ryekids.com/about/) > [**OFFICE POLICIES**](https://ryekids.com/about/office-policies/)

Appointment Policy
------------------

Your appointment is reserved specifically for your child. Changes may affect many other patients. If a change or cancellation is unavoidable and conflicts arise, please call us at the office at least 48 business hours (2 days) in advance so that we may offer that time to another patient who is in need of care.

As a courtesy to you and your child, we contact you via phone, email, and/or text to confirm your child’s appointment. Please let the front staff know your preference, and we will make the appropriate arrangements. We usually email one week before appointments, and call the day before to confirm your scheduled appointment.

We make every possible attempt to see all patients at their scheduled appointment time. In rare instances, our schedule may be adjusted in order to accommodate an injured child or an emergency situation. Please accept our deepest apology in advance should this occur during your appointment.

We will provide your child with the same courtesy should the unfortunate need for emergency treatment arise.

Please plan to arrive 5 minutes or more before your scheduled appointment. This will allow time for the completion of any additional paperwork so that your child’s visit remains on time.

A parent or legal guardian should be present during the first visit in order to sign all legal documents and consent to treatment. With these appropriate forms, grandparents, au pairs, and caretakers are permitted to accompany children for subsequent appointments. It would be our pleasure to meet your extended family so that we may provide home care instructions to all of your child’s caretakers.

Privacy Policy
--------------

Our office understands the importance of protecting your personal information. Please be assured that the collection, use, and disclosure of your personal information will be done in accordance with the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act (HIPAA). We appreciate your understanding in helping Rye Pediatric Dentistry remain in compliance with this law.

_Disclaimer:_  
Our website is meant to provide general information to you and your family about pediatric dentistry. Since each child’s oral health needs are unique, the content of this website does not provide specific professional advice. It should not be used as a substitute for consulting with a pediatric dentist.

To obtain recommendations appropriate for your child, please contact us for an appointment or consult any pediatric dentist of your choice. We shall not be liable for any dental and oral health related problems allegedly arising from the information disclosed in our website.

Financial Policy
----------------

Arrangment of payment for professional services is due at the time dental treatment is provided. Every effort will be made to provide a treatment plan which fits your timetable and budget, and gives your child the best possible care.

The office accepts Visa, MasterCard, Discover, and American Express. In addition, we offer several financing options, including Care Credit and in house financial payment arrangements. We are a preferred provider with several insurance companies and will happily file insurance claims. Please contact the office by email or call us: (914) 967-0000 for more information.

Voted Best Dentist by  
Westchester Magazine

© 2021 Rye Pediatric Dentistry, P.C. All Rights Reserved.

[Call](tel:+1 (914)967-0000)
